

# Ganesh Kutty

959 595 9750 | **E:** ganeshkutty2257767@gmail.com A-24, Karan Gharonda, Sainikwadi, Vadgaonsheri, Pune, Maharashtra 411014

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Game Tester with over 1.5 years of experience in Gaming Industry. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, troubleshooting and playthrough tasks. Experienced in Report and test case creation.

Talented Java/Android Developer with 6 months of experience in IT Industry.

Currently pursuing Data Science Master certification from Marsian Technologies Ltd.

# SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Selenium WebDriver.
- Back End Development using PHP, MySQL, MongoDB.
- Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, Python, RUBY.
- Hardware: Beagle Bone Black, Arduino and Raspberry Pi.
- Cyber Security Techniques: IP Spoofing, Steganography and Honeypot Implementation.

- Basic knowledge of shell programming in Linux, and Assembly Level Programming.
- Game testing tools such as Xbox
   One Manager, Xbox Live Account
   Tool and Xbox Live Trace

   Analyzer.
- Documentation and Reporting using Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word and Microsoft Outlook.
- Test case development and reviewing.

# **WORK HISTORY**

## **GAME TEST ENGINEER**

09/2017 to 06/2019

### GlobalStep Services Pvt Ltd | Pune, MH

- Performed Compliance Testing on Xbox One X platform using the latest Xbox One Games and Apps Requirements and Test Cases.
- Wrote and optimized test cases to maximize success of testing with consistent, thorough approaches.
- Tracked and reported defects into Bug Databases such as Bonsai, Mantis, JIRA and Test Track Pro.
- Efficient at writing, reviewing and uploading bugs into databases.
- Performed performance testing for Intel on high end PC configurations on various titles.
- Created and reviewed reports to be delivered to Clients in the absence of Team Lead.
- Performed network testing on multiplayer titles with varying bandwidth and bandwidth limitations.
- Efficient at using tools like Xbox One Manager, FRAPS and trdrop.
- Tested 63 titles for Compliance defects.

#### JAVA/ANDROID DEVELOPER

12/2016 to 06/2017

### Transworld Technologies Ltd. | Pune, MH

Developed robust Java code for Vehicle Tracking system applications.

- Utilized knowledge of javascript, Ajax and Node.js to supplement Java development.
- Maintained existing applications and designed and delivered new applications.
- Created custom mobile applications using native technologies as per client specifications.

#### **EDUCATION** $\bigcirc$

**10th SSC** 2010

# Saraswati Vidyalaya High School, Pune MH

Passed with 92%.

12th HSC | Science 2012

# Nowrosjee Wadia College, Pune, MH

Passed with 78%.

Bachelor of Engineering | Computer Science 2016

Modern Education Society's College of Engineering, Pune, MH

# PROJECTS

# Virtual Reality Gaming | Final Year Engineering | April 2016

Developed an app that tracks the user playing the game and transmits the data to a web-server using well placed sensors, LED's and lasers.

• The main objective was to promote the use of IOT(Internet Of Things).

# Bot With Gripper | College Robotics Event | August 2014

Designed a remote-controlled Bot with a working gripper that was capable of grabbing, lifting and transporting small objects.

• This bot could be controlled over a wireless network as well as using physical wires.

# LEADERSHIP/TEAM SKILLS

- Member of Robotics Club, while at College.
- Member of NSS team, while at College, organizing two camps, and awareness rallies.
- Coordinator for Association Of Computer Engineers (ACE) (2013-2014).
- Mentor for underprivileged kids at Akansha Foundation(June December 2014).
- Coordinator for Digital Renaissance LAN Gaming held in College(2015).
- Coordinator for National Service Scheme (2013 2015), where I participated in one rural development camp (visited a village for 7 days, interacted with the locals, and helped them by providing a solution to a few of their issues.)
- Coordinated in Swatchha Bharat Abhiyaan where we cleaned a part of the city.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Published a paper titled "Internet Of Things Changing The Game" in International Journal Of Scientific And Technology Research (IJSTR).
- Developed a Unique Identification(UID), Aadhar like system using PHP,

- MySQL, HTML, CSS and JS as a minor project in Third Year of College.
- Presented a seminar in college on "Emerging Cyber World Attack Vectors" and presented a report on the same.
- Won a Gold Medal in Open Bout of International Shotokan Karate Institute's (ISKI) fight.
- Won a Silver Medal in Kata Competition organized by International Shotokan Karate Institute (ISKI).

# EXTRA CURRICULAR

- Participated in the college fashion show, "Hues Of India" organized by College Cultural Committee for NAAC.
- Attended a two-day entrepreneurship development camp at college, organized by Entrepreneurship Development Institute and Department Of Science And Technology, Government Of India, March 2015.
- Played Piano as the lead Pianist in college band Eminence for Jhankaar 2016.
- Hobbies include Gaming, Swimming, Football, Roller skating, Wave boarding, Solving Rubik's Cube, Playing Piano.